# Manish Sondhi

Email: Manishsondhi94@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://manish-portfolio-resume.netlify.app/#portfolio

Call: (609)-816-5121

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative UI/UX Designer with 4+ years of facilitating and supporting human interactions with complex systems and software.
 Maintains user-centric designs while adhering to prescribed interface principles and related development goals. Dedicated to creating inviting and unintimidating interfaces for everything from simple open-source applications to complex proprietary systems. Well-qualified Font-End knowledge familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages.
 Knowledgeable of frontend development requirements. Handles any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

CYNC Software Herndon, VA

UI/UX Designer

02/2022-Present

02/2020-02/2022

- Worked closely with product owners to establish requirements and create an AWS-based offering.
- Lead Designer for Collateral, which enables lenders to add, maintain, and pledge the collateral that will be used to secure a loan and guide decision-making for loss given default (LGD) risk ratings.
- Lead Designer for Relationship, feature collects extensive information regarding every type of entity in one convenient location while providing quick access to the other services needed to work and maintain the relationship during the life of the loan.
- Utilize the React.js design framework and style guide to maintain uniformity throughout the application.
- Use Microsoft Forms to conduct user research surveys to compile and assess user needs for testing, working with product managers, designers, and engineers.
- Showcase design concepts with the use of storyboards, user flows, and sitemaps.
- Create scalable visual user interface elements for the program, including as menus, tabs, and components.
- Use Confluence and Jira, two cloud-based technologies, to effectively communicate and write documentation.
- Using Adobe XD, create high-fidelity wireframes.
- Developing and documenting business requirements: Analyzing business processes and identifying opportunities for improvement, gathering, and documenting user requirements, and creating process models and diagrams.
- Analyzing data: Collecting, organizing, and analyzing data to identify trends and patterns, and to develop insights and recommendations.
- Designing solutions: Developing solutions to address business needs and creating detailed specifications for implementation.
- Developing test plans: Developing and executing test plans to ensure that solutions meet business requirements.
- Supporting implementation: Supporting the implementation of new solutions and providing training and user support.
- Managing projects: Defining project scope and objectives, developing project plans, and managing project resources.
- Monitoring performance: Monitoring the performance of existing solutions and recommending changes to improve performance.
- Building relationships: Building relationships with stakeholders to ensure that solutions meet their needs.
- Identifying risks: Identifying potential risks and developing strategies to mitigate them.
- Developing reports: Developing reports to track progress and performance.
- User interface components such as CTAs, layouts, target links, landing pages, and banner ads should all be put through rigorous testing.
- Creating full stack solutions and continuous delivery frameworks to help the teams who develop financial lending software produce solutions more quickly and with higher quality.
- Conducted a variety of UX techniques to uncover pain points that allow for educated decision making (journey mapping, use-cases, information architecture, user flows, user interviews, personas, wireframes, usability testing, A/B testing, and data analysis).
- Good amount of knowledge in developing and maintaining applications using JSX, React.JS,
- Extensive knowledge in the application's main architecture is using Micro-Frontend.
- Good understanding in designing web pages using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React.JS
- Used react-router to turn the application into Single Page Application
- Great knowledge with React components, Forms, Events, Keys, Router
- Good knowledge with Jest to render the react component in an object and then in the memory instead of in the DOM.
- Involve yourself in all aspects of design, development, and testing daily.
- Test the responsiveness of the program for the end user.

Bank of America New York

- Creating rapid prototypes to validate design concepts.
- leading/facilitating design activities and prototype workshops.
- Talked to users and other stakeholders to gather needs, then quickly drawing out wireframes to illustrate the concepts being discussed.
- Guided conversations to develop and subsequently validate UI concepts and metaphors.
- Worked with front-end UI analysis, user/task analysis, and interviewing.
- low quality prototypes are made, then tested with users.
- Used Adobe XD to build high-fidelity prototypes based on user demands and business objectives, then pitching those concepts to other teams around the enterprise.
- Worked closely with development teams to make sure designs are technically feasible within authorized frameworks and overseeing the development of the interface.
- Supported the execution of UI concepts and design approaches.
- Advanced user interface (UI) design and development techniques that encourage reuse and boost efficiency.
- Applications developed using Angular 11 and Bootstrap as the front-end framework, with Typescript, CSS3, and HTML5.
- Used NPM for installing required node modules and other published Angular NPM modules.
- Followed Agile methodologies and work closely with Scrum Master and Product Owner to prioritize the stories.
- Worked Extensively with Angular CLI for creating components, Services, pipes, Directives.
- Responsible for developing UI pages using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap JSON, Angular11.
- Developed style sheets using CSS pre-processors SASS.
- Used Angular 11 Template Driven forms and Modern Driven (Reactive) forms to perform form validations both on server and client side.
- Used Decorators to optimize the code reusability and worked with services, providers in Angular 11.
- Experience in working with Routes in Angular 11.
- Customized components for each of the web page in Angular 11.
- Implemented HTML5 feature like semantics, local storage, data and required attributes and sliders.

# TD Bank

Absecon, NJ & Newark, NJ & Secaucus, NJ

01/2014 - 11/2018

- Bank Teller/Customer Service Representative
  - Cash handling through withdrawals, deposits, and payments
  - Awareness of bank location's vulnerability to fraud
  - Satisfactory customer service through building lasting relations with customers and recommending products in the clients' best interest
  - ATM machine and coin machine maintenance
  - Experience using the TCR and TCD machines
  - Taking responsibility for the main and coin vault during the supervisor's absence
  - Responsible for ensuring that client assets are protected by opening and closing accounts in compliance with established operational rules.
  - Manages and maintains client account information using the new accounts system database.
  - Customers' safe deposit boxes are opened and closed in accordance with safe deposit box regulations and procedures.
  - Responds to consumer inquiries over the phone and help them with their banking requirements.
  - Responds quickly, effectively, and professionally to customer queries and normal account requests, investigates, and resolves account service inquiries and problems, and assists customers with routine account requests.
  - Responsible for performing teller duties in line with the job description for Tellers
  - By aggressively cross-selling and promoting new and existing items and services to present and future clients, marketing strategies are used to establish connections.
  - An overall client experience that is good is the goal of this position.
  - Contributes to the department's culture of cooperation
  - Management may delegate additional responsibilities to the employee.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Science in Information Technology**

2022

Southern New Hampshire University

## **PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION**

Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design